techbout.com 2019-05-19

# Privacy Policy - Techbout

Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or handle data of visitors to this website (techbout.com).

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information that you may provide to third-party websites and services that this website may link to.

### What Information Do We Collect

Anonymous information like web pages visited, browsers used (Chrome, Safari, IE, etc), devices used (PC, Phone, Tablet),  Referring sites, number of visitors to the website is made available to us by web servers and analytics programs.

If you use services like Facebook and Twitter, they may know that you have visited this website.

We do not process payments or sell Goods or services on this website. Hence, we do not collect personal information like your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, payment information and other details.

If you happen to contact us by email, you are expected to provide us with your name and email address.

### Measuring Visitors

We use Google Analytics to measure visitors to this website in an anonymous manner.

Google Analytics provides us with information like the pages that you visited, how you arrived at our site, time spent on specific web pages and other such anonymous and non personally identifying information – So we don’t really know who you are.

Having access to such information in Google Analytics helps us understand what type of content visitors prefer, how people arrive at our website and how long they stay on our website.

Like most websites, we use this information to make our website better. You can learn more about Google Analytics or opt out if you wish.

### Use of Cookies

We are able to provide high quality free content to our readers by allowing advertisers to place relevant Ads on our website. These advertisers generally use cookies to make advertising more effective and relevant to the users.

Advertisers/vendors may collect information to measure and monitor their advertising campaigns and have their own privacy policies.

We do not have any control over cookies placed by advertisers and are not responsible or liable in any way for the collection and use of information by such advertisers/vendors.

If you do not want cookies, you can set up your computer to warn you whenever a website tries to install cookies and you can even [disable cookies](https://www.techbout.com/enable-disable-cookies-on-chrome-6773/) in your web browser.

If you disable cookies, you may be unable to use or experience the full functionality of this website and advertisers won’t be able to serve you with relevant ads.

### Third-party Links and Ads

While reviewing, comparing and listing Gadgets, we generally provide links to Amazon and other sellers, so that you can check current prices, offers and deals on those products.

Once you leave this website by clicking on links or advertisements on this website, you are entirely governed by privacy policies of the websites that you land on.

The external websites may use cookies to track visitor behaviour, measure effectiveness of their advertising programs and for other purposes.

You are advised to check the privacy policies of those external websites and interact with them only when you find them reputable and you are satisfied with their privacy policies.

### Email Privacy

In order to contact us, you are required to provide your name and email address, so that we can reply back to you.

We make no efforts to collect, retain or preserve emails and do not use this information for marketing purposes and will never share this information with any third parties.

### Children and Minors

Our service is not directed to children under the age of sixteen. If you are under the age of sixteen, you must ask your parent or guardian for permission to use this website.

If we find that we have received any personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will take reasonable steps to delete that information as quickly as possible.

### Embedded content from other websites

Some articles on this website may contain embedded content in the form of YouTube videos or content from other websites.

Since embedded content is served directly from other websites, interacting with embedded content on any website should be treated as actually visiting these websites.

Hence, you are requested to refer to privacy policies of these external websites, in order to learn more about what user data they collect and how they use this information.

### Updates to this policy

We may update this privacy policy from time-to-time, particularly as technology changes. You can always check this page for the latest version.

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or your personal data, please email to techbout@hotmail.com.
